SAMANTHA YEE

Los Angeles, CA 90005 | (425) 922 3914 | <u>samantha.yee11@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/samantha-e-yee/</u> | Portfolio: <u>www.sam-yee.com</u>

UX Designer with a background in Sales and Marketing. Skills in Web Development, Qualitative UX Research, and Information Architecture. Competitive nature gives me strengths in productivity, teamwork, and a determination to always learn and develop new skills to create the best products that help the world become more connected, beautiful, and user friendly. Created focus groups in a recent project with teens aged 9-14 and based wireframes of apps off the responses to help them discuss their technology usage with their parents in a fun and engaging way. Sales background coupled with web development and animations expertise gives me the ability to leverage an adaptable and success driven approach on any team.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Web Development: Animations, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery. | **UX/UI:** Adobe Creative Cloud, InVision, Storyboards, Decision Flow Diagrams and Mapping, Qualitative and Quantitative Research, User Experience Interviews, UI Grids and Composition, Color Theory, Proto-Personas, Interface and Visual Design, Interaction Design and Iconography. Thoughtful and elegant writing capabilities for customer facing content (website content, training documents, FAQ). Ability to work with cross functional teams including software engineering, sales and marketing. | **Productivity:** Object Oriented Programming in Java and C++. Data programming in R and SQL.

PROJECTS

WEST HOLLYWOOD ELEMENTARY - https://www.sam-yee.com/projects/WeHoElementary/westHollywood.html Group Project - COVID-19 Case Study and Responsive Website Redesign

- My role: User Research, Systematic Ideation, Wireframing, High Fidelity prototyping, Front End Development.
- A solution based on interviewee's problems from the switch to virtual learning the COVID-19 Pandemic has caused.
- Using Adobe XD for wireframing to a high fidelity interactive prototype with animated microinteractions.

USDA.GOV REDESIGN - https://www.sam-yee.com/projects/USDA/USDA.html

Personal Project - Government Responsive Website Redesignand Content Strategy

- A responsive website redesign of the United States Department of Agriculture's website made for their primary users.
- User empathy demonstrated with user flows, an updated sitemap with better information architecture, and User Personas.
- UI Style Guide, Social Media Rules, and updated branding for the USDA that can easily be used for future designs.

$\textbf{SAVE THE WHALES REDESIGN} - \underline{\text{https://www.sam-yee.com/projects/SaveTheWhales/SaveTheWhales.html}}$

Personal Project - NonProfit Responsive Website Redesign and Donation Research

- A responsive website redesign of the Save The Whales nonprofit website with user testing on impact of key features.
- In depth user research of user's primary concerns with nonprofits and the best way they can help a cause.
- Clear ideation with user insights, problem statements, feature prioritization matrix, and interactive wireframes.
- Front end development of the front page complete with responsive media queries and Javascript interactions.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

THE THRIFT COLLECTIVE

UX Designer 04/2020 -

Present

- Oversaw the UX of the desktop and mobile version of the website from scratch at the creation of the company.
- Used design to change the stigma of thrift shopping by creating a UX that features sustainability, community, and style.
- Coordinated Information Architecture that showcases a complex shop and a sustainability blog with important resources.
- Maximized time with other departments to increase visibility and provide the best UX before the websites launch.

KIDSTEAM UW

UX Design Research Assistant for Professor Jason Yip

02/2019 - 03/2020

- Working with the iSchool and the Human Centered Design & Engineering department at the University of Washington to facilitate a study that co-designs with children to make UX design recommendations across numerous platforms.
- Performing qualitative data analysis by encoding data in a Code Book from research I planned and conducted.
- Advocated data-based design decisions for LoFi interactive wireframes that offer solutions to the problems uncovered.

BUNGEETECH

UX Designer Consultant Intern

06/2017 - 09/2017

• UX design of the Bungeetech.com website, customer dashboard, and browser extension for Chrome and Firefox.

- Assisting rapid wireframing and prototyping of the UI, responsive web, and information architecture.
- Making parsimonious, data-driven recommendations for design changes based on the UX and company style guide.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

CLOUD KITCHENS

Account Executive 04/2020 -

Present

• Working with graphic design teams to help make virtual restaurants and using KPIs to optimize them for success.

DOCUSIGN

Sales Development Representative Intern

Spring 2019

• Designing a talk track using quick thinking, good listening, and an empathetic skill set then highlighting info for other teams. **AMAZON**

Account Executive Intern

Summer 2018

- Creating reports for programmatic advertising KPIs and assisting Advertising to become one of the most profitable branches.
- Creating slide decks and presenting important ad words data to enterprise clients to help them raise their ROI and optimize.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA IRVINE

Irvine, CA

UX/UI Certificate Bootcamp

10/2020

• CGPA 4.0. Refining skills across all stages of the UX process from research to ideation to prototyping to coding.

SEATTLE UNIVERSITY

Seattle, WA

Programming Bootcamp

09/2019

• Object-oriented programming, data structures, and system fundamentals to gain industry knowledge across all areas of CS. UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON Seattle, WA

BA in Communication; Minor in Informatics; Professional Sales Certificate Foster School of Business

06/2019

• CGPA 3.4. Specializing in public relations strategy and visual communication. Minor degrees focusing on the relationship between information, technology, people, and marketing.